<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Notebook | CyrusN</title>
    <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Notebook | CyrusN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 14:11:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cyrusn.github.io/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Zero OTG Mode</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/raspberry-pi-zero-otg-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 14:11:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/raspberry-pi-zero-otg-mode/</guid>
      <description>Setting for OTG mode for pi zero instruction  add the following text to /boot/config.txt
# Enable OTG mode dtoverlay=dwc2  Save the config.txt file as plain text and then open up cmdline.txt After rootwait (the last word on the first line) add a space and then modules-load=dwc2,g_ether
 Create an empty file named as ssh.txt in /boot
 connect to your pi through ssh
# default password is raspberry ssh pi@raspberrypi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Input and Output</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/input-and-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 21:08:06 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/input-and-output/</guid>
      <description>ADC  Analog to Digital Conversion - learn.sparkfun.com  MCP3008  MCP3008 | Raspberry Pi Analog to Digital Converters | Adafruit Learning System 14. API - SPI Devices — Gpiozero 1.4.1 Documentation Raspberry Pi ADC: MCP3008 Analog to Digital Converter  I2C sensors  I2C - learn.sparkfun.com  MPU6050 (Gyroscope)  MCP3008 | Raspberry Pi Analog to Digital Converters | Adafruit Learning System GY-521 MPU6050模块 三维角度传感器6DOF 三轴加速度计电子陀螺仪-tmall.com天猫 GitHub - Tijndagamer/mpu6050: A Python module for accessing the MPU-6050 digital accelerometer and gyroscope on a Raspberry Pi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stem for kids</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/stem_for_kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 17:21:08 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/stem_for_kids/</guid>
      <description> References  Coding for Kids-A Guide for Teachers and Parents | Udemy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Setup</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/raspberry-pi-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 21:10:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/raspberry-pi-setup/</guid>
      <description>Setup for a new Pi Download the latest version of Raspbian Stretch and download Etcher app to flash the raspbian image to SD card. Plug the flashed SD card to your raspberry and power it on.
Update and upgrade Open terminal app and run the following command to update and upgrade the packages and OS.
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get upgrade  Config the localisation options Run sudo raspi-config for changing the following settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RetroPie</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/retropie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 09:35:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/retropie/</guid>
      <description> Introduction  How to Build a Raspberry Pi Retro Game Console First Installation - RetroPie Docs  ROM  SNES ROMs | Emuparadise Super Mario World (J) - SNES ROM | Complete ROMs  Setup 8bitdo controller  8Bitdo - RetroPie Docs !! READ THIS FIRST !! - RetroPie Forum 8Bitdo Zero How to Setup in Retropie 4.2 – RobbysWeb.com  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auth in Golang</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/auth-in-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 11:51:54 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/auth-in-golang/</guid>
      <description>Concept Example  Example of using middleware  Reference  Concept JWT have 3 session, header, payload and signature. Information are stored in payload session which can be read without authentication, therefore no secret information should be stored there. Server parses JWT token stored in header in every http request for authenticated.
In server side, using middelware for http.Handler function if the request are involved with authentication. System can also store user information like username and scope in JWT payload session further usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latex</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 09:21:44 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/latex/</guid>
      <description> Cheat Sheet  Download  Using displaystyle We can use \displaystyle to make font look better, here is the difference.
 Add nothing or using \textstyle   The quadratic equation is $\textstyle x = \frac{-b\pm\sqrt{b^2-4ac}}{2a}$
  Using \displaystyle   The quadratic equation is $\displaystyle x = \frac{-b\pm\sqrt{b^2-4ac}}{2a}$
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 08:28:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/photography/</guid>
      <description> Be a Better Photographer in 45 mins     Exposure Triangle   Metering     Reference  超詳盡攝影教學！101個新手必學的攝影技巧 - 攝影入門 Fotobeginner.com 9 Top Photography Composition Rules You Need To Know A Picture To Show You Clearly The Effects of Aperture, Shutter Speed and ISO On Images  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABCJS</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/abcjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:39:19 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/abcjs/</guid>
      <description>References  paulrosen/abcjs: javascript for rendering abc music notation ABC Music Notation  Example - Lyrics Score   Code     X: 1 T: Misirlou C: N.Roubanis 1934 O: Greece M: 4/4 L: 1/8 K: Gm % |: &#34;D&#34;D3 E ^F2 G2 | A3B ^c2BA | A8- | A8 | w: 1.~Mi-sir-lou mou i gli-kia sou ma-tia w: 2.~Mav-ro ma-ta Mi-sir-lou mou tre-lli | D3E ^F2G2 | A3B ^c2BA | A8- | A8 | w: Flo-ga m&#39;e-hi~i-na-psi mes tin kar-dia w: Ti zo-i m&#39;al-la-zo me-na fi-li      X: 1 T: Misirlou C: N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backing Voice</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/backing-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:29:10 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/backing-voice/</guid>
      <description>黃金時代 Score   Code     T: 黃金時代 K: D M: 4/4 L: 1/8 V:1 name=&#34;Vocal&#34; V:2 name=&#34;Chorus&#34; % [V:1] &#34;D&#34;dA/2A/2 -Ad &#34;A&#34;cA/2A/2 z2 |&#34;G&#34;Bd/2d/2 -dG &#34;A&#34;F2 E2| w: 你 和 誰 - 結 伴 前 來 是 否 比 - 我 精 采 [V:2] fd/2d/2 -df ec/2c/2 z2 |z8|      T: 黃金時代 K: D M: 4/4 L: 1/8 V:1 name=&#34;Vocal&#34; V:2 name=&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jazz</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/jazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 21:28:46 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/jazz/</guid>
      <description> Score   Code     K: C &#34;Dm7&#34;[DCF]|&#34;G7&#34;[GBDF]|&#34;Cmaj7&#34;[CEGB]||      K: C &#34;Dm7&#34;[DCF]|&#34;G7&#34;[GBDF]|&#34;Cmaj7&#34;[CEGB]||       ABCJS.renderAbc(&#39;abcjs-src-1&#39;, &#39;\nK: C\n\x22Dm7\x22[DCF]|\x22G7\x22[GBDF]|\x22Cmaj7\x22[CEGB]||\n&#39;, {}, { &#39;responsive&#39;: &#39;resize&#39;, &#39;add_classes&#39;: true }, { })  This is the basic chord of jazz music.
References  Jazz harmony - Wikiwand  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/graphql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 01:47:41 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/graphql/</guid>
      <description> Reference  The steady rise of GraphQL – freeCodeCamp  Passage with alot of reference for GraphQL  graphql with go and postgresql  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STEM Curriculum for Hong Kong</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/stem_curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 15:15:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/stem_curriculum/</guid>
      <description>Model  TPACK SMAR SetoWS_CoE_20170221_public (for EDB Web)  Curriculum design  first year  learning tasks / experiment on suitable topics  second year  learning tasks / experiment on suitable topics maybe simple project  third year  learning (1st term) tasks / experiment on suitable topics final project (2nd term)   Content Which topic should be included in the curriculum for students whose age are 12 - 16?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Design</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/software-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 08:43:26 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/software-design/</guid>
      <description>SDD (Software design document) Template  TOC Introduction  Purpose Scope Overview  System Overview System Architecture  Architecture Design Decomposition Description Design Rationale  Data Design  Data Description Data Dictionary  Component Design Human Interface Design  Overview of User Interface Screen Images Screen Objects and Actions  Requirements Matrix  Cucumber and Gherkin  Writing Features - Gherkin Language — Behat 2.5.3 documentation Reference·Cucumber How To Write Well-Formed User Stories Business Analyst | User Stories and Use Cases - Don’t Use Both!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Design Counseling</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/life_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 19:09:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/life_design/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  定訂是次會面的目標 以下落黎我會好似記者咁去訪問你，有D問題，你隨意去諗答案，唔駛有壓力  Questions Q1. Role Models Objective: Identify adjectives that describe a client’s construction and conception of self.   你細個有咩好深刻好特別又記得既人，你幾欣賞，對你都幾大影響既人。
  Summarise 你既感受 仲大無 D 人你諗起？ 仲有無邊 D 人你想講？ 你點形容呢個人 點樣形容佢對你身上既影響 佢地有咩共通點 佢地呢D生命既特質，同你有無D相似  Q2. Magazines, Television,Websites Objective: Identify the types of environments and activities that interest the client.   不如我地去第二條囉，你有無D咩鐘意既雜誌、網站、電視節目呀，你經常去睇？
  有咩覺得咁吸引？ 我睇到你好享受&amp;hellip;，你總結一下你既興趣係咩？  Q3. Favorite Story Objective: Understand the stories or cultural scripts that a client may be using to envision the transition outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Resources</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/math-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 14:32:46 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/math-resources/</guid>
      <description> $$ \alpha $$
Reference  資源下載 - 超研教育｜中學數學補習社｜Band 1補習學府｜補習課程｜暑期班 CE, DSE Maths Pastpaper &amp;amp; Marking Scheme 歷屆試題 | 知新教育 學校沒有教的數學 (Part 1-Q1-14) 2015 DSE 數學卷一長問題 Math Paper 1 應該暫時係最詳細既答案 - 經數樂園－學習變有趣～  Past Paper ans  數學補習 | 數學 2015 paper II 卷二 詳細答案 - Knight Mathematics 數學補習 - 中學專科數學補習社 - DSE數學 - IB/IGCSE/GCE - 自修生 CE and DSE Maths Marking Scheme – mathspercyyeung  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 21:38:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/python/</guid>
      <description> Tools  Format String  Games  Programming Fundamentals: 15 Puzzle Game - (In Python) The Python Challenge  pyqt  Riverbank | Software | PyQt | What is PyQt? PyQt Tutorial Python Programming Tutorials Intro/basic GUI - PyQt with Python GUI Programming tutorial - YouTube Tetris in PyQt5  tkinter (legacy)  Forget tkinter, which is designed 20 years ago
  Tkinter object-oriented app example Introduction to GUI programming with tkinter — Object-Oriented Programming in Python 1 documentation  References  Python 3 Module of the Week — PyMOTW 3 Python Tutorials – Real Python  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:44:09 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Basic setting  Setup guide for raspberry pi  Autostart Use sudo crontab -e to set autostart programme
@reboot python /home/pi/MyScript.py &amp;amp;  This tells Cron that every boot (or reboot or start-up) we want to run Python with the script MyScript.py. The “&amp;amp;” at the end of the line means the command is run in the background and it won’t stop the system booting up as before.
To kill the job</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yakko&#39;s World Lyric</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/yakko-s-world-lyric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 21:31:16 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/yakko-s-world-lyric/</guid>
      <description>United States, Canada, Mexico, Panama Haiti, Jamaica, Peru,
Republic Dominican, Cuba, Carribbean Greenland, El Salvador too.
Puerto Rico, Columbia, Venezuela Honduras, Guyana, and still,
Guatemala, Bolivia, then Argentina And Ecuador, Chile, Brazil.
Costa Rica, Belize, Nicaragua, Bermuda Bahamas, Tobago, San Juan,
Paraguay, Uruguay, Surinam And French Guiana Barbados, and Guam.
Norway, and Sweden, and Iceland, and Finland and Germany now ~ want peace,
Switzerland, Austria, Czech, Slovakia Italy, Turkey, and Greece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 10:58:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/education/</guid>
      <description>  學校課程持續更新 STEM C&amp;amp;A  學校課程持續更新  學校課程持續更新  STEM  科學教育課程指引 (小一至中六) 數學教育課程指引 (小一至中六) 《推動STEM教育 — 發揮創意潛能》報告 科技教育課程指引 (小一至中六)  C&amp;amp;A  課程文件 專案名稱： read_attach.php  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TSF</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/tsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 17:09:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/tsf/</guid>
      <description>var students = [{ name: &#39;foo&#39;, clazz: &#39;4A&#39; }, { name: &#39;world&#39;, clazz: &#39;4B&#39; }, { name: &#39;bar&#39;, clazz: &#39;4B&#39; }, { name: &#39;hello&#39;, clazz: &#39;4C&#39; }] var clazzes = [&#39;4B&#39;, &#39;4C&#39;] clazzes.forEach(function (clazz) { students.filter(createFilterFunction(clazz)).forEach(logName) }) function createFilterFunction (clazz) { // return filterFunction return function (student) { return student.clazz === clazz } } function logName (student) { console.log(student.name) }  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grammar</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/grammar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 07:48:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/grammar/</guid>
      <description>English grammar 101
Tenses     Present Tenses in English Simple present tense  The simple present tense is one of several forms of present tense in English. It is used to describe habits, unchanging situations, general truths, and fixed arrangements. The simple present tense is simple to form. Just use the base form of the verb: (I take, you take, we take, they take) The 3rd person singular takes an -s at the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>swimming</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 23:02:28 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/swimming/</guid>
      <description> FreeStyle  3 Drills to Improve Freestyle Stroke | Swimming Lessons - YouTube Speedo&amp;rsquo;s Ultimate Guide to a Perfect Freestyle Swim Stroke! (Tutorial) - Presented by ProTriathlon - YouTube  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sql</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 20:56:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/sql/</guid>
      <description>Some of The Most Important SQL Commands  SELECT - extracts data from a database UPDATE - updates data in a database DELETE - deletes data from a database INSERT INTO - inserts new data into a database CREATE DATABASE - creates a new database ALTER DATABASE - modifies a database CREATE TABLE - creates a new table ALTER TABLE - modifies a table DROP TABLE - deletes a table CREATE INDEX - creates an index (search key) DROP INDEX - deletes an index  SQL PRIMARY KEY Constraint The PRIMARY KEY constraint uniquely identifies each record in a database table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dyson Washing</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/dyson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/dyson/</guid>
      <description> How to clean the Dyson V6 / DC59 Cordless Vacuum Cleaner - YouTube Dyson V6 Absolute and V6 Mattress - Washing the filters (Official Dyson video) - YouTube  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STEM Idea on Education</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/stem-idea-on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 19:05:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/stem-idea-on-education/</guid>
      <description>STEM chanllege Innovative Ideas (Think by Discipline) Coding and Math Reference Statistic Engineering Some Idea from 青年會書院 Ideas Model on STEM Education Resource  STEM chanllege  making stuff  make a plane, it can fly as long as possible. make a bridge, it can weigh as heavy as possible. make a phone, it can talk as far as possible  Solve some puzzle  decode an encrypted message   Innovative Ideas (Think by Discipline)  Health  Elderly Care Smart Home Smoke Detector falling Detector Silent Detector Bionics Eyes  Climate Change Challenge / Envoirnment  typhoon disaster Sewage Handling Extreme Heat / Cold Bio Disel storm surges terrential rains Prevent 4D Jobs (Dull, Dirty, Dangerous)   Coding and Math Reference  Computer Science (Not Just Coding) Needs a Bigger Role in STEM Education | EdTech Magazine UC Davis Center for Integrated Computing and STEM Education Zebra Puzzle - Wikiwand The Micro:bit Foundation is a global non-profit organisation making invention with technology fun for everyone!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on PCVEPT Course</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/pcvpet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 10:57:07 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/pcvpet/</guid>
      <description>Notes on PCVPET  Vocational Education in Hong Kong
 Blue Collar Why MTR always out of order? The Event of Langham Place Air Conditional / escalator  only fill up 25% of needs  Is that because the lack development of Vocational Training? Hong Kong need technician Student need to find what they will devote in and capable of. Earn And Learn Scheme 3 days works and 3 days study Pages - VPETCITY Home  Simple Game</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google calendar for LPSS colleagues</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/google-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 09:50:13 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/google-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Add Calendar to mobile devices  Login your LiPing domain account in the web browser first  Go to www.google.com username: lpXXX@liping.edu.hk password: please ask ITAV team if you didn’t get the password  Go to calendar view or press this link https://calendar.google.com/calendar Go to Other Calendar section and paste the link below to the box “Add a colleague’s calendar”  liping.edu.hk_0jfuie399d0elvaac06k0hur8o@group.calendar.google.com   Then you will see the word “School Calendar” under the Other Calendar section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>臺灣升學 Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/taiwan-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 23:13:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/taiwan-study/</guid>
      <description>Useful Links  學士班適用簡章2017 Q&amp;amp;A 來台就學費用估算 入學暨來臺相關規定 赴臺升學小冊子(新版).pdf.pdf)  資格 「僑生」指海外出生連續居留迄今，或最近連續居留海外六年以上，並取得僑居地永久或長期居留證件回國就學之華裔學生。 但就讀大學醫學、牙醫及中醫學系者，其連續居留年限為八年以上。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4C&#43;1X 升學考慮</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/4&#43;1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 23:12:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/4&#43;1/</guid>
      <description> JUPAS 各大學入學要求  4C+2X (3322+33)  HKU CUHK HKUST PolyU  4C+2X (3322+22)  CityU  4C+1X (2018年要求：3322+3)  HKBU  4C+1X (3322+2)  LU EdUHK OUHK SSSDP   Reference  JUPAS Website  Accept M as X  CityU CUHK PolyU HKUST HKU (部分課程)  HD / AD  基本入學要求：22 + 222  Taiwan 個人申請  跟據校內成績、讀書計劃及師長推薦  聯合分發  中英數 ＋ 2科（包括通識），詳見下表。  Reference  香港學生適用簡章(PDF)   Mainland  內地免試招生  按個別內地大學收生準則而定 一般普通類別收生要求為4C (3322) 部分大學會提高要求（頂尖大學），只考慮修讀4C+2X的學生  Reference  內地部分高校免試招生香港學生計劃指南2016-17   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Theory</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/career-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 14:21:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/career-theory/</guid>
      <description> Donal Super Theory  Super&amp;rsquo;s Career Development Theory - IResearchNet career-theory-model-super.pdf The Life Career Rainbow - Get a better work/life balance - Career Development from MindTools.com  Reference  LifeDesign.pdf Holland’s Theory of Career Choice | Career Key The Big Five Career Theories The Serious Leisure Perspective (SLP) - Welcome Careers and Career Information - CareerOneStop Free Personality Test | 16Personalities    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Startup Script in Linux</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/create-startup-script-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 12:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/create-startup-script-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>Create a new script in /etc/init.d/myscript.
vi /etc/init.d/myscript  (Obviously it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be called &amp;ldquo;myscript&amp;rdquo;.) In this script, do whatever you want to do. Perhaps just run the script you mentioned. #!/bin/sh /path/to/my/script.sh  Make it executable.
chmod 755 /etc/init.d/myscript  Configure the init system to run this script at startup.
update-rc.d myscript defaults  ystem to run this script at startup.
update-rc.d myscript defaults  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Digital Ocean Kernel</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/update-digital-ocean-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 21:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/update-digital-ocean-kernel/</guid>
      <description>Check Which Kernel is Currently in Use
To display both the kernel version and your system&amp;rsquo;s architecture (32-bit or 64-bit), type: uname -ir  Upgrading All Packages and Using the Newest Kernel sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get dist-upgrade sudo reboot sudo apt-get install update-manager-core sudo do-release-upgrade  Reference How To Upgrade to Ubuntu 16.04 LTS | DigitalOcean How To Update a DigitalOcean Server&amp;rsquo;s Kernel | DigitalOcean</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caddy Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/caddy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 07:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/caddy/</guid>
      <description> Installation # install caddy in linux commandline curl -fsSL https://getcaddy.com | bash -s search  Settng of Caddyfile for microservice TODO Make Caddy to serve https  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS and JWT</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/https-and-jwt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 23:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/https-and-jwt/</guid>
      <description> Links  Self-signed certificate - Wikiwand Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt - Free SSL/TLS Certificates JWT, JWS and JWE for Not So Dummies! JSON Web Token Series - YouTube  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Authentication</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/web-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/web-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Notes  Authentication in Golang with JWTs Cookies vs Tokens: The Definitive Guide The Ins and Outs of Token Based Authentication | Scotch  Enterprise APIs and OAuth: Have it All Secure your users&amp;rsquo; passwords from the browser on  Authentication Protocols  Basic access authentication - Wikiwand Digest access authentication - Wikiwand Secure Remote Password protocol - Wikiwand
 Anatomy of a zero-knowledge web application - Clipperz, register your creations on the blockchain</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIM Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 11:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/vim/</guid>
      <description>VIM Basic  amix/vimrc: The ultimate Vim configuration: vimrc Vim Cheat Sheet - English VimGenius vimgifs  Some useful skills Update VIM Pathogen Plugin for i in ~/.vim/bundle/*; do git -C $i pull; done
Insert across multi-lines Select the lines you want to modify using Ctrl-v. Press: I: Insert before what&amp;rsquo;s selected. A: Append after what&amp;rsquo;s selected. c: Replace what&amp;rsquo;s selected. Type the new text. Press Esc to apply the changes to all selected lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 23:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker - Build, Ship, and Run Any App, Anywhere</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Config Digital Ocean Droplet as Microservice</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/config-digtal-ocean-droplet-as-microservice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 08:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/config-digtal-ocean-droplet-as-microservice/</guid>
      <description>Objective This page is a notes for setting apache server for my digital ocean droplet
Setting Apache2  in file /etc/hosts
 change 127.0.0.1 localhost to 127.0.1.1 localhost WordPress-CaLP-LPSS  change Port
 in file /etc/apache2/port.conf add ServerName localhost change the line listen *:80 to listen 127.0.0.1:4000 disable other modules &amp;lt;IfModule ssl_module&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;IfModule mod_gnutls.c&amp;gt; in file /etc/apache2/site-enabled/000-default.conf change the line &amp;lt;VirtualHost *:80&amp;gt; to &amp;lt;VirtualHost localhost:4000&amp;gt;  restart apache2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to convert images to gif</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/how-to-convert-pngs-to-gif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 07:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/how-to-convert-pngs-to-gif/</guid>
      <description> install imagemagick through homebrew $ brew install imagemagick  convert pngs to gif with 2 second per frame $ convert -delay 200 *.png converted.gif  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open SSL</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/open-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 21:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/open-ssl/</guid>
      <description>OpenSSL is a toolkit for the TLS and SSL. The Most Common OpenSSL Commands key/cert types X.509 - Wikiwand DER vs. CRT vs. CER vs. PEM Certificates and How To Convert Them .pem == .crt == X.509? probably .key == .csr == DER? probably not, .csr can be converted to .crt .pfx/.p12 == PKCS#12
key: no meta data, just the prime numbers and moduluses cert: with meta data
cert generation How to create a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSL TLS</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/ssl-tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 21:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/ssl-tls/</guid>
      <description>Transport Layer Security (TLS) and its predecessor, Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), are cryptographic protocols designed to provide communications security over a computer network.
The authentication relied on Certificate Authorities (CA) and a public key infrastructure using X.509 certificates. The server register with a CA and sign its public key with the key of CA for a fee. The client, after receiving the public key from server, verifies it with the CA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Ocean Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/digital-ocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 12:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/digital-ocean/</guid>
      <description> connect to console # prepare ssh keys first # login droplet ssh root@ip.of.the.droplet # to copy a file from B to A while logged into B scp /path/to/file username@a:/path/to/destination # to copy a file from B to A while logged into A scp username@b:/path/to/file /path/to/destination  perpare ssh key  How To Use SSH Keys with DigitalOcean Droplets | DigitalOcean  achieve  Save a snapshot and delete droplet restore droplet by the snapshot  Update Server&amp;rsquo;s Kernel  How To Update a DigitalOcean Server&amp;rsquo;s Kernel | DigitalOcean  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>macos Setting Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/macos-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 13:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/macos-setting/</guid>
      <description>Custom OSX  Remove shift key augmentation for Mission Control animation Enable the three finger drag in Accessibility  Terminal  Autocomplete echo &amp;quot;set completion-ignore-case On&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.inputrc install command line tools in XCode xcode-select --install  zsh  install .oh-my-zsh symlink for setting zsh  ## for installation of zsh ln -s Dropbox/MacSetting/Terminal/cyrusn ./.cyrusn ln -s ~/Dropbox/MacSetting/Terminal/zsh/.zshrc ~/ ln -s ~/Dropbox/MacSetting/Terminal/zsh/.zsh-custom ~/ ## for installation of coreutil/.dir_colors ln -s ~/Dropbox/MacSetting/Terminal/coreutil/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfred Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/alfred/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 23:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/alfred/</guid>
      <description> How to use node on alfred workflow node&amp;lt;&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;code&amp;quot; // your code here // e.g. console.log(&amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot;); code  iTerm2 Integration curl --silent &#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stuartcryan/custom-iterm-applescripts-for-alfred/master/custom_iterm_script_iterm_2.9.applescript&#39; | pbcopy   stuartcryan/custom-iterm-applescripts-for-alfred: Custom iTerm Applescripts for Alfred  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome App</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/google-chrome-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 07:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/google-chrome-app/</guid>
      <description> Links  Adblock Plus - Chrome Web Store Tampermonkey - Chrome Web Store Wikiwand: Wikipedia Modernized - Chrome Web Store Markdown Preview Plus - Chrome Web Store Postman - REST Client - Chrome Web Store  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Concept</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/programming-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 08:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/programming-concept/</guid>
      <description>Links leesei&amp;rsquo;s choice  Naming What can I learn right now in just 10 minutes that could be useful for the rest of my programming career?  Programming Principal reference  Links  How to make your code self-documenting? | CodeUtopia Separation of concerns - Wikipedia Garbage in, garbage out - Wikiwand  leesei&amp;rsquo;s choice Naming  寫出黎就要俾名，俾名啲concept 就清楚，code 亦自然清楚
 What can I learn right now in just 10 minutes that could be useful for the rest of my programming career?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript on OSAScript</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/javascript-on-osascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 12:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/javascript-on-osascript/</guid>
      <description>Example  JXA-Cookbook Apple Release Notes JavaScript for OS X Automation by Example  Display Notification #! /usr/bin/osascript -l JavaScript app = Application.currentApplication(); app.includeStandardAdditions = true; app.displayNotification(&#39;Hello, world&#39;, {withtitle: &#39;Title&#39;})  example // alfred workflow // convert Google Chrome active tab to markdown link function run(argz) { var app = Application.currentApplication(); app.includeStandardAdditions = true; var Chrome = Application(&#39;Google Chrome&#39;); var activeTab = Chrome.windows[@0].activeTab; var result = &#39;[&#39; + activeTab.title() + &#39;](&#39; + activeTab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Command Line Tools</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/useful-command-line-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 22:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/useful-command-line-tools/</guid>
      <description>Basic Redirect operators # pipe echo &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot; | sed &#39;s/ /_/&#39; # redirect the standard output result to file (replace) echo &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot; &amp;gt; test.txt # redirect the standard output result to file (append) echo &amp;quot;hello world&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; test.txt # redirect file to standard input # e.g. replace all space to _ in text.txt and save to a new file sed &#39;s/ /_/g&#39; &amp;lt; test.txt &amp;gt; test_1.txt # line input cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; end heredoc&amp;gt; hello heredoc&amp;gt; world heredoc&amp;gt; end  Create multiple files or folders mkdir sa{1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardware Architecture</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/hardware-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 17:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/hardware-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Basic  Hardware Basics - YouTube  what is legacy FGA: &amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo; is not a pejorative. Do not use it as such.
BIOS POST -&amp;gt; BIOS -&amp;gt; MBR of boot partition -&amp;gt; Bootloader -&amp;gt; Kernel -&amp;gt; init/systemd -&amp;gt; shell/display manager -&amp;gt; startx/xinit
UEFI Unified Extensible Firmware Interface - ArchWiki</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google App Script</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/google-app-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 11:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/google-app-script/</guid>
      <description>Links  Apps Script | Google Developers  Using html request to send form response  open inspecter in google form (view version, not editable one) find the input Tag of the question and copy it&amp;rsquo;s name. The name look like entry.933828429 replace the word view in the link to formResponse  https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdC2RD1aD4W4duLGDjxsVFDGvJW6IUhhxsBGWiQlV7TU_w5LA/formResponse  add the query to the end of the link look like above  ?entry.933828429=Hello%20World where %20 mean space  if you need another question&amp;rsquo;s response, use &amp;amp; as seperator, like below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draw More Work Less</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/draw-more-work-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 01:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/draw-more-work-less/</guid>
      <description>Some Links from leesei  Text based tools GaaS (graph as a service) GUI Tools   Some Links UML | leesei&amp;rsquo;s notebook Draw More, Work Less | [self employed] Draw More, Work Less PlantUML Mermaid
from leesei Unified Modeling Language (UML) Business Process Model and Notation (BPMN) is very similar to activity diagram. YANG Central
Allen Holub&amp;rsquo;s UML Quick Reference
Text based tools I used to use the GUI tool Dia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/react/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 01:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/react/</guid>
      <description>API notes and example  Top-Level API Component API Component Specs and ifecycle Tags and Attributes Event System  Ref Links Concept  React | A JavaScript library for building user interfaces Reactive MVC and the Virtual DOM &amp;ndash; Futurice ReactJS For Stupid People Component Interop With React And Custom Elements Josh Haberman: React Demystified Intro to the React Framework | Nettuts+ Integrating React and Flux with Angular  Tutorial  Learning React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic CS Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/basic-cs-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 01:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/basic-cs-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>打底班  Programming Languages - YouTube Hardware Basics - YouTube Operating System Basics - YouTube  Free Courses  Coursera - Free Online Courses From Top Universities  JavaScript  JavaScript Not Working? Here are 10 Common JavaScript Problems | Toptal Learn All The Nodes Node Tuts // leesei: 我兩年前都係睇 Pedro，佢最近拍過晒 JSConf - YouTube // leesei: 好很多，太舊唔洗睇  property, protoypal inheritance  JavaScript: proto Object properties in JavaScript Properties in JavaScript: definition versus assignment JavaScript terminology: the two prototypes JavaScript properties: inheritance and enumerability JavaScript inheritance by example JavaScript inheritance: beyond the basics (video) Property assignment and the prototype chain A closer look at _.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/git/</guid>
      <description>start a new repo $ git init # add repo $ git remote add origin https://github.com/user/repo.git  change existing repo $ git remote rm origin $ git remote add origin https://github.com/user/repo.git  create a new branch and merge # on latest commit $ git checkout -b &amp;lt;branch_name&amp;gt; # create new branch # do you work $ git commit -a # edit the commit log as details as possible $ git checkout master $ git merge &amp;lt;branch_name&amp;gt; # double check everything, if ok then push.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mongoose.js and MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/mongoose.js-and-mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/mongoose.js-and-mongodb/</guid>
      <description>Custom _id  你schema 有 _id mongo 就唔同你gen, 亦唔可以用 Schema.ObjectId 做ref, 會認唔到type 的 可以令 _id 有意思,
 e.g. studentSchema, use regno as custom _id e.g. teacherSchema, use teacherInitial as custom _id  use uuid if you need to have id before add new stuff
 e.g. attachmentSchema, need the id to rename the attachment before saving to database.   Schema.ObjectId  if no need to use custom _id then use Schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/golang/</guid>
      <description>Useful commands  update all packages go get -u all  Feautre  Embedding  Understanding Goroutine  Is golang goroutine a coroutine? Coroutine vs Continuation vs Generator Comparison with generators  MongoDB  mgo Painless Data Storage with MongoDB and Go Connecting to MongoDB with mgo and golang  Router  mux - Gorilla, the golang web toolkit  # Middleware
 justinas/alice: Painless middleware chaining for Go  Database Model Architecture  Go database/sql tutorial Practical Persistence in Go: Organising Database Access Practical Persistence in Go: SQL Databases How to use databases with Golang – Hacker Noon Architecture for a Golang Web App - Larry Price Trying Clean Architecture on Golang – Hacker Noon Applying The Clean Architecture to Go applications » The Log Book of Manuel Kiessling  Authentication  dgrijalva/jwt-go: Golang implementation of JSON Web Tokens (JWT) Golang Authentication Using JSON Web Tokens  Useful Package  PuerkitoBio/goquery: A little like that j-thing, only in Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitbook Notes</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/gitbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/gitbook/</guid>
      <description>  Gitbook Modern book format and toolchain using Git and Markdown  Useful Plugins  katex sectionx responsive-iframes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>豬腳薑烹調方法</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/pigs-feet-ginger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 00:50:22 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/pigs-feet-ginger/</guid>
      <description>豬腳薑烹調方法 每斤薑最少要一斤甜醋才能浸過面，所以5斤薑一定要5斤甜醋才足夠。 器材: 瓦煲首選，新瓦煲應用水浸過夜，然後再用。瓦煲的容量，5斤薑及5斤醋最小也要用10斤瓦煲 (未計豬腳及雞蛋) 。如用10斤薑及10斤醋自然最小也要用20斤瓦煲 (未計豬腳及雞蛋) ，如此類推。
材料： 悅和特級甜醋，薑，豬腳，雞蛋，悅和黑糯米醋，鹽。婦女產後補身應用老薑，平常食用可用籽薑 (即煲即食) 。購買豬腳時應選擇可靠的肉檔，採用新鮮嫩豬手。
準備工作：刮薑，烘乾 刮薑時薑用小刀去皮後，用水冲淨，拍裂小許，晒乾至爽身或用小量油、鹽於鑊中慢火煎乾，備用。婦女坐月時薑皮也可留起煲水抹身驅風。
 清洗薑身表面。 將薑皮清理乾清。 婦女坐月時薑皮可用留起煲水抹身。 把薑件拍扁備用。 晒乾至爽身或將薑件落鑊慢火，小油，小鹽，烘乾。  烹調方法： 浸薑醋－先用甜醋煮薑。把炒好的薑件放入瓦煲內，砌好然後再加入甜醋。反之如先落甜醋然後落薑，因薑是浮水的，甜醋末必能蓋過薑面。
烹調要點： 起火用中火 (文火) ，太大火會將瓦煲煮裂，煲滾後，調至小火，繼續煲45分至60分後熄火，蓋好放屋內陰秋涼處，夏天每7至10天再煲滾一次，秋涼或冬天可10至15天再煲一次，滾後15分鐘立即熄火，如是大概煲兩至叁次後至小孩出世後備用。
豬腳薑： 將已煮好的薑醋加入豬腳及雞蛋。此時根據個人的喜好，加入適量的腳手或豬腳，但要留意豬脚及豬手均要飛水去油，雞蛋煮熟後去殼，連同豬腳一齊燜腍可即食用。
特級甜醋味道適中，適合一般家庭的口味，但如煲次數太多，水份及酸味揮發，薑醋會愈煲愈甜，此時可加入本廠的黑糯米醋，調至個人口味，重新煲滾即可食用。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>炒米茶</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/chao-mi-cha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 00:44:01 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/note/chao-mi-cha/</guid>
      <description>炒米茶 其實炒米茶(代茶)的作用, 是加強新陳代謝, 紓緩身體不適情況,另外產婦大多有胃寒情況,經常口淡淡,若果飲用一般滾水會增加口淡感覺, 容易出現作悶, 若不斷喝水, 就很容易出現胃脹.尿頻.便秘.腳水腫情況, 飲用代茶則可改善情況.所以產婦一般都會飲用代茶至滿月為止!!
先說說用料&amp;hellip;
炒米: 可以用：白米、紅米、糙米、黑糯米(會較前者為補)，全部一齊撈埋炒都可以，只選其一亦可! 不過建議如果是夏季出生的寶寶媽, 其實也不需太補, 否則會太過燥熱呢! 恐怕虛不受補呢!
材料：  炒米 陳皮 (順產可以轉用薑) 元肉 杞子 淮山 黑豆 (餵人奶媽媽可以加黑豆去炒, 因為黑豆可以增加奶量, 不過一定要清晒惡露先好飲,因為黑豆好補血) 南棗 (順產適用)  注意事項
 紅棗、當歸勿用，因會旺血 陳皮越耐、越多年越好，建議用7年以上既陳皮，咁就唔駛去囊，因為去囊要沉水15分鐘後再用匙刮去囊，咁樣一齊入茶包袋好易會令到其他材料濕哂而變壞。 順產用薑建議飲時先加，唔好一齊入茶包袋，因為會令到其他材料濕哂而變壞。 所有材料都唔需要洗，保持乾爽，到飲用既時候，過一次熱水後，第二次既熱水就可以焗15分鐘飲得，每一包炒米茶可以返焗2-3次。  份量隨心： 炒米(2湯匙西式果d匙)、陳皮(隨心)、圓肉(5粒)、杞子(隨心)
第一日：炒米（泰國紅米）＋ 陳皮 (順產可以用薑)
第二日：炒米（泰國紅米）＋ 陳皮 ＋ 圓肉
第三日直至坐完月：炒米（泰國紅米）＋ 陳皮 ＋ 圓肉 ＋ 杞子 (開刀生者適用)
第四日直至坐完月：炒米（泰國紅米）＋ 陳皮 ＋ 圓肉 ＋ 杞子 ＋ 南棗（順產生者適用）
開刀生B者, 只需要 &amp;ldquo;第一日、第二日、第三日&amp;rdquo; 順產生B者, 可整哂 &amp;ldquo;第一日、第二日、第三日、第四日&amp;rdquo;
整好後入密實袋壓走多餘空氣, 收好係放係雪櫃就可以架啦, 到入院既時候記得帶埋去醫院就okay。</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>