<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Notebook | CyrusN</title>
    <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Notebook | CyrusN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 14:11:49 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cyrusn.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Zero OTG Mode</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/raspberry-pi-zero-otg-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 14:11:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/raspberry-pi-zero-otg-mode/</guid>
      <description>Setting for OTG mode for pi zero Instruction  add the following text to /boot/config.txt
# Enable OTG mode dtoverlay=dwc2  Save the config.txt file as plain text and then open up cmdline.txt After rootwait (the last word on the first line) add a space and then modules-load=dwc2,g_ether
 Create an empty file named as ssh.txt in /boot
 connect to your pi through ssh
# default password is raspberry ssh pi@raspberrypi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Setup</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/raspberry-pi-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 21:10:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/raspberry-pi-setup/</guid>
      <description>Setup for a new Pi Download the latest version of Raspbian Stretch and download Etcher app to flash the raspbian image to SD card. Plug the flashed SD card to your raspberry and power it on.
Update and upgrade Open terminal app and run the following command to update and upgrade the packages and OS.
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get upgrade  Config the localisation options Run sudo raspi-config for changing the following settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google calendar for LPSS colleagues</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/google-calendar-lpss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 09:50:13 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/google-calendar-lpss/</guid>
      <description>Add Calendar to mobile devices  Login your LiPing domain account in the web browser first  Go to www.google.com username: lpXXX@liping.edu.hk password: please ask ITAV team if you didn’t get the password  Go to calendar view or press this link https://calendar.google.com/calendar Go to Other Calendar section and paste the link below to the box “Add a colleague’s calendar”  liping.edu.hk_0jfuie399d0elvaac06k0hur8o@group.calendar.google.com   Then you will see the word “School Calendar” under the Other Calendar section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download YouTube in batch</title>
      <link>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/download-youtube-in-batch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 23:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>cyrusncy@gmail.com (CyrusN)</author>
      <guid>https://cyrusn.github.io/post/download-youtube-in-batch/</guid>
      <description>youtube-dl Sometime I have to download many YouTube videos or songs, if you are using mac or linux, youtube-dl would be a very handy and useful tool to get the job done. youtube-dl is a command-line interface application which the plain text environment may deter you to give a try, but once you can get used to it, you will find that using command-line application somehow are much easier than GUI (Graphical User Interface) application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>